Finding aid to the Smith College International Summer Institute records CA.MS.00085
Smith College Archives
Smith College International Summer Institute records
1996-1999
Smith College Archives
Smith College. International Summer Institute.
CA.MS.00085
2.083 linear feet (5 containers)
The program offered high school girls, foreign nationals or U.S. citizens living abroad, an opportunity to spend one month at Smith pursuing their academic interests. Records contain primarily correspondence, evaluation forms, course descriptions, student work, photographs, and general information about the Institute.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith College International Summer Institute was proposed in 1996. The program offered high school girls, who were foreign nationals or U.S. citizens living abroad, an opportunity to spend one month at Smith pursuing their academic interests. The program was divided into two blocks of two weeks each in which the students would study computer science, English, psychology and economics while also working on individual research projects. The Institute operated successfully during the summer of 1997 with 13 students from 11 different countries. The program for the summer of 1998 was cancelled in late May.
Scope and Contents
The International Summer Institute files, contain primarily correspondence, publicity, photos and general information about the Institute. Of particular note are the evaluation forms regarding the quality of the program, course descriptions and examples of some of the research projects completed by participants in 1997.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series:
I. Program Information
II. Restricted Information
III. Student Files RESTRICTED
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use with following restrictions on access: Budget materials are closed for 25 years from the date of creation and information about student participants and staff is closed for 75 years from the date of creation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records of the Smith College International Summer Institute were delivered to the College Archives by the director of the program, Kathleen Lyu Ryan, in August, 1999. Accession #: 99A-98
Summer schools--Massachusetts--Northampton.; Women--Education--Massachusetts--Northampton.; Smith College. International Summer Institute.
- Series I. Program Information
  Scope and Contents
  This series is unrestricted information about the Institute and its activities.
  - Agendas, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1997-98 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brochures, 1997-98 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Calendar and Room Assignments, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Contacts, 1996-97 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1997-99 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Courses, 1997-98 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Evaluations, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Fall Reunion, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Forms/Originals, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General Information, 1997-98 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Grant Proposals, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Host Dinners, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Inquiries, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Inquiries, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Job Descriptions and Blank Applications, 1997-98 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kathleen Ryan's Lists of Things to Do, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Liberty High School, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Notebook, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Notebook, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Other Programs Information, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Participant Information, 1997-98 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Photos, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Preparation for Participants, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Proposals and Reports, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Publicity/Publications, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Publicity, 1997-98 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Publicity for 1998, 1997-98 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Student Handbook, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Student Packet Sample, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Student Work, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Training for Residential Directors and Interns, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Video and Picture Release, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Young Women's Leadership School of East Harlem, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series II. Restricted Information
  This series contains files that are closed due to their confidential nature. The budget and billing materials are restricted for 25 years from the date of creation while the materials on students and staff are restricted for 75 years from the date of creation.
  - Applicants, 1997-98 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bills, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1997-98 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Financial Aid, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Interns and Residential Directors, 1997-98 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Professor Contracts, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Student and Intern Profiles, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Series III. Student Files RESTRICTED
  This series contains the files of the students who were accepted into the program for 1997 and 1998 and are restricted for 75 years from the date of creation.
  - Adenika, Remi - Nigeria, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Chang, Dana - Taiwan, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Chatzikonstantinou, Eleni - Greece, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Chatzidimitriou, Stavroula (Julia) - Greece, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hatzichrstou, Styliani - Greece, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Kerr, Kathleen - New Zealand, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Khan, Farah - Bangladesh, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Materassi, Luisa - Italy, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Nedialkova, Teodora (Titi) - Bulgaria, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rykovanova, Ekaterina - Russia, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sawara, Naoko - Japan, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Tallberg, Linda - Finland, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Taran, Alexandra - Hong Kong, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Batalska, Tatiana - Bulgaria [did not attend], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Carol, Yu Wing Ka - Hong Kong [did not attend], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Georgieva, Gergana D. - Bulgaria [did not attend], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Khor, Fenny - Malaysia [did not attend], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kung, Cee - China [did not attend], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Malik, Zainab - Taiwan [did not attend], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Weisfelt, Romy - Australia [did not attend], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Yusuf, Mehreen - Bangladesh [did not attend], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Al Bakree, Basma - Saudi Arabia, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Alemu, Hlina - Ethiopia, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Arabadjiyska, Aneta - Bulgaria, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Bwalya, Chileshe - Zambia, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Chien, Liang-Ru (Laura) - Taiwan, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Fynn, Rosy - Ghana, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Grashkin, Alexandra - Bulgaria, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Jaskot, Katarzyna - Poland, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Khan, Maria Moin - Pakistan, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Koeva, Martina - Bulgaria, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Kurdi, Ghazal - Saudi Arabia, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Pinarbasi, Bahar - Turkey, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Tsutsui, Kimiko - Japan, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Zaman, Jawziya - Pakistan, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 27)